Hello everyone, a very warm welcome to all of you.
You are watching You The Real. I am your
own personal advisor Amitraj Sharma. The credit for today's
video goes to Mr. Neeraj for
this comment. Neeraj ji,
thank you very much for your comment. As you all know, every
video on the channel
comes daily based on your questions, suggestions and comments. So, do tell us in the comment section
which plan you want the next video to be
about.
To get videos as per your requirement, stay connected to the channel.
For that, like and share the video. Do
n't forget to subscribe to the channel and turn on all the notification bells. In today's video,
we are going to understand the details of Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance's
Vision Money Back Plus plan.
This plan is a non-linked
participating life insurance plan. This
means that the company does not invest the premium you pay under this plan
in equity or stocks. Therefore,
you do not face market related risks like equity stocks. It is a participating plan, which
means that at the end of the financial year, if the
insurance company announces a bonus, it is
paid to you guaranteed. This
means that the benefits under this plan are
To see the combination, you get
guaranteed as well as non-guaranteed benefits.
So let us first learn
about the benefits of Aditya Bilal Sal Life Insurance Company Limited's Vision Money Back Plus Plan. The first benefit
you get is survival benefit, which you
call money back benefit. You get two options
whether you
want money back every 4 years during the policy term or you want money back
every 5 years. For
example, you are seeing on the screen that if you have taken a
policy term of 20 years with a premium payment term of 10 years or a policy term of 24 years
with a premium payment term of 12 years and if
you want money back every 4 years, then the
first time you will get money back will be 10% of
your sum assured, whether you
take a premium payment term of 10 years or a
premium payment term of 12 years, or a
policy term of 20 years or 24 years. Now
what will happen after that, after every 4 years gap?  The 55%
money back will keep increasing here
because there is a
positive term of 20 years with a premium payment term of 10 years, so the
last installment of money back
in the 20th year will be 30% of your sum assured. The same will
apply with a pause term of 24 years as
well, but when the 24th year is completed, you will
get 35% of your sum assured as
money back. But if you want it at a gap of every 5 years, then the
money back that you will get for the first time will be
15% only in the fifth year,
whether it is a premium payment term of 10 years with a
policy term of 20 years or a
premium payment term of 12 years with a policy term of
25 years. Right, after that,
this amount will increase by 55% every time,
but in the end, you will
get a higher amount. How, 20% in the 10th year,
25% in the 15th year and if you have taken a policy term of 20 years, then
your basic sum in the 20th year
You get 40% of the sum assured,
but if you have taken a policy term of 25 years with a
premium payment term of 12 years,
then in the 20th year you get a money back of 30% of your basic sum assured.
As soon as the 25th
year is completed, if you have taken a premium payment term of 12 years and a premium
payment term of 25 years, then
you will get a money back of 45% of your basic sum assured. So, while
listening to the video, only then
you will get the information. On
maturity, you get
whatever simple
reversionary bonus you have accumulated during the policy term and if the
company has announced a terminal bonus, then when it comes to
death benefit, then along with the sum assured on
death, the simple reversionary bonus
and terminal bonus, if any, are paid to the nominee.
In the same plan, you also get the facility to enhance your
guaranteed benefit, i.e. the survival
benefit, that is,
if you have
kept the survival benefit with the company without taking it,
it is available.  If there is, then that is also available in the form of death benefit.
This facility is called
Enhanced Survival Benefit. Now, by how much
percentage it will increase depends on the policy
term, premium payment term and the number of deferred
years you have taken. For example, we are
seeing on the screen,
premium payment term of 10 years, policy term of 20 years.
So, we know that after the gap of fifth year,
we are getting survival benefit here. So,
I have written every fifth
year, right. So, the first time guaranteed
survival benefit that will be applicable will be
15% of the basic sum assured. Now, suppose you did not
take this and left it with the company, now the
second installment of money back will
be 20% of your basic sum assured. So,
when you have to get this second installment of money back,
20% of your basic sum assured,
then the first 15% of the basic sum assured that you have
left with the company, right will increase to
20%, that is, it will increase by 5% and will be given on the
10th.
If you wish to
take it along with the annual money back installment, if you do not wish to take it, then the
third installment will come in the 15th year, 15% of your basic
sum amount, 25% of the money back, so the
money back that you have left for the fifth year will
increase to
25% of your basic sum amount, and as soon as the
20th year is completed, you will again get the
money back installment, suppose
you did not take the money back even in the 15th year,
but you took the remaining money back of 5 years, then
now the money back of the 15th year which was
25% of the basic sum amount, the money back of the 20th
year which is
40% of the basic sum amount will be given along with it, how much will you get,
instead of 25% it will become
33% of the basic sum amount, that is, the amount of the 15th year
also gets increased, so this is
how it works, let us now
know here Aditya Billa Sunlife
Regarding the eligibility criteria for the Vision Money Back Plus plan, the
age limit for taking the plan is from 13
years to 45 years, that is, 13
to 45 years. There are three policy term options:
20 years, 24 years, and 25 years. If you take a 10-year
premium payment term,
you get a policy term of 20 years.
However, if you take a 12-year premium
payment term, you
get the option of a 24-year and 25-year policy term. The
minimum sum assured limit is
₹1. The premium depends on
your age at the time of taking the plan, the policy
term, the premium payment term,
and the sum assured you take.
Now, let us take
a small example to understand the benefits of the Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance Vision Money Back Plus plan. Let us assume that
Mr. A is 35 years old and is
taking a policy term of 20 years.  year
i.e. premium payment term is 10 years,
he is taking basic sum assured
of ₹ lakh and he wants to keep getting money back every 5
years, so
for this the base premium he will pay annually will be
₹ 2500000
first installment as % of basic sum assured
which is ₹ lakh, then in the 10th year he will get
% of ₹ lakh, then in the 15th year he will get 25%,
then in the 20th year he will get 40%, okay
now we have to see the amount of money back here,
how much will we get, so if we take out % of ₹ lakh on sum
assured it will be ₹ 7500,
if you take out 20% of ₹ lakh then it will become
₹ 5000000, second installment and in the
15th year he will get the third installment
which will be 25% of ₹ lakh i.e.
62500 and as soon as the 20th  The year will be completing, at
that time, we will get 40% money back on ₹1 lakh, that is,
₹1 lakh, so our
total sum assured is equal to ours,
here they would have got the survival benefit
till the maturity, okay, now the question
comes that
what do we need to know to get the maturity benefit, the
bonus rate is from ₹33.50 paise to
₹1 lakh on a sum assured of ₹0.000, if the sum
assured is ₹1 lakh or more, then
our ₹1 lakh is the sum added, so the
bonus rate here, we are assuming on the average lower side, that is,
33.50 paise on a sum assured of ₹0.000, that is,
3.3% of the sum assured, so if we take out 3.35% of one lakh and
multiply it by 20, then the simple reversionary bonus
becomes ₹
67500, now in this the terminal  Bonus will be added
which only the company will be able to tell exactly
and they will get this amount on maturity.
Okay, now let us assume that
Mr. A dies after completion of 6 years of the policy, then
in such a situation we will have to
first know the sum assured on death. To
calculate the sum assured on death, if we multiply the annual premium by
10, then this amount will be
26250 because the annual
premium is 26225, if we compare it with the base sum
assured which is ₹ lakh, then
226 will be more than 22250, this will be the sum
assured. Now to calculate the bonus accumulated in 6 years, we will
multiply our sum assured of ₹ lakh by applying the bonus rate on it,
then the award here will be Simple
Reversionary Bonus of 50250, which we have written
in short as a.s.  If it is written then
what is the death benefit, yes sum added death along with simple
reversionary bonus and terminal bonus i.e.
31500 plus terminal bonus if any then the company will pay it
and the plan will close there itself.
Now in this plan you get riders
like accidental death and
disability rider, critical illness rider,
surgical care rider along with that hospital
care rider, then there is waiver of premium rider
and the last rider you get to see is
accidental death benefit
rider plus right, you people
asked to know about the rider in the comment section, a
video related to this will come soon right,
so stay tuned to the channel. When it comes to the free
look up period, you get a 15 day free look
up period if you
take the plan directly from the insurance company, if
not then you get a 30 day free look up period,
during this time period you
can cancel the policy and get
your amount back after tax, so this is the
main basic information
related to this plan, after listening to which you
take the plan, now in the next video  You will also
get to know more information like
what is surrender value and how exactly the enhanced survival benefit will
work with examples. To avoid the
video becoming too long,
we are dividing it into two parts.
Thank you very much for patiently watching the video till the end. Many thanks and
gratitude to you for understanding one thing yourself and
explain it to others as well that insurance is a protection.
Protection is never taken incompletely. If the
information is clear then like the video.